A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of the Secretary and General Counsel, Grant Records, Organizational Grants FA1510
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Recommended Grant Action Forms and Affirmative Action Statements, 1
  - Women's Legal Defense Fund, 1978-1984 (Box 6, Folder 251)
    1980 July - Partial support for a Joint Project of WLDF with Women Employed Institute to achieve improved enforcement of equal opportunity laws through monitoring, policy development and advocacy
    1978 April - Program to monitor the effectiveness of the federal civil rights enforcement agencies
  - Women's Research and Education Institute - Washington, D.C., 1980-1985 (Box 6, Folder 252)
    1985 October - Partial support for the creation of an annual report on the Status of American Women
    1984 October - Continued support for a program of coordination and dissemination of policy-related research from national women's policy and research centers (Supplement 800-0590)
    1982 August - Continued support for a program of coordination and dissemination of policy-related research from national women's policy and research centers (Supplement 800-0590)
    1980 July - Support for a Program of Research Coordination
  - Women's Resource Center - Grand Rapids, Michigan, 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 253)
    1978 April - Supplemental and Terminal Support of Job Opportunity Advocacy Program and Other Activities
    1975 April - Expansion of Job Opportunity Advocacy Program and replication of services in other communities
    1976 April - Michigan Assembly on Women in the American Economy
  - Women's Technical Institute (WTI), 1981 November (Box 6, Folder 254)
  - Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, 1974-1986 (Box 6, Folder 255)
    1986 June - Support to expand and strengthen the Center's programs in international affairs (Supplement 830-0453)
    1982 July - Support for the Latin American Program
    1978 August - Partial support of seminars and dialogues on the role of the states in the federal system
    1979 December - Support for the Center's Latin American Program (formerly read "support for a program of research seminars on Inter-American affairs") Supplement No. 1
    1974 May - Support of a fellowship program for government officials and other professionals in state and local government
    1976 September - Support for a program of research and seminars on Inter-American affairs
    1983 May - Project support to promote imaginative new projects in international affairs and public outreach
  - Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation, 1974 September (Box 6, Folder 256)
    Continuation of Fellowship Program for Research on the role of Women in Society
  - Worcester Foundation for Experimental Biology, Inc., 1974 January (Box 6, Folder 257)
    Support for studies on anti-fertility compounds, Supplement No. 1
  - Worcester Polytechnic Institute (Mass.), 1974 (Box 6, Folder 258)
    1974 June - Venture Fund grants to Northeastern institutions in support of innovations in undergraduate education
    1974 April - Partial support for the Public/Private Forum and for a conference concerning higher education in Massachusetts
  - The Work in America Institute, Inc., 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 259)
    1978 January - Continued support of the Institute's programs to aid in improving the quality of working life
    1975 May - Support of projects designed to aid in improving organizational effectiveness and enhancing the quality of working life
    1975 December - Continued General Support of the Exxon Institute's efforts to improve organizational effectiveness and the quality of working life
  - The Working Theatre, New York, Inc., 1975 October (Box 6, Folder 260)
    Partial support of a demonstration of methods for training teachers for the theater
  - Working Women Education Fund, 1981-1985 (Box 6, Folder 261)
    1985 September - To continue a program of research, public education and advocacy to widen opportunities for female office workers
    1983 November - To continue a program of research, public education and advocacy to widen opportunities for female office workers
    1981 November - To continue a program of research, public education and advocacy to widen opportunities for female office workers
  - Working Women's Forum - India, 1983 May (Box 6, Folder 262)
    Support for strengthening the FOrum's management and technical capacity and its credit cooperatives in rural areas
  - World Education, Inc., 1974-1982 (Box 6, Folder 263)
    International workshop for evaluation specialists on non-formal education for family life planning (835-0047)
  - World Neighbors, 1986 June (Box 6, Folder 264)
    Support for experimental community-based maternal and child health projects in Eastern Africa
  - World Priorities, 1984 May (Box 6, Folder 265)
    Planning activities, seminars and publications related to the 1985 United Nations Inter-Governmental World Conference on Women and the Parallel NGO Forum
  - World Resources Institute, 1983 September (Box 6, Folder 266)
    Partial support to initiate the annual publication of a World Resources Report
  - World University Service in the United Kingdom, 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 267)
    1985 July - Support for the establishment of a refugee employment office in Kenya
    1984 February - Study to identify employment opportunities for educated refugees from the Horn of Africa
    1982 January - Study to identify employment opportunities for educated refugees from the Horn of Africa
  - Worldwatch Institute, 1978 March (Box 6, Folder 268)
    Study of world forest trends
  - Writers and Scholars Educational Trust, 1981-1986 (Box 6, Folder 269)
    1986 June - Support for monitoring problems of freedom of expression worldwide, reporting on cases of censorship and publishing writings of censored authors
    1984 May - Support for monitoring problems of freedom of expression worldwide and reporting on cases of censorships
    1981 July - Support for action and research relating to censorship and other abuses of intellectual freedom, Supplement No. 2
  - Wycombe Foundation (Zimbabwe), 1983 September (Box 6, Folder 270)
    Support for development of savings clubs in Zimbabwe and surrounding countries
  - Xavier Labour Relations Institute (India), 1982 August (Box 6, Folder 271)
    Support for planning, managerial and educational aspects of community forestry programs in Bihar
  - Xavier University (Louisiana), 1981-1986 (Box 6, Folder 272)
    1986 May - Projects in literacy and the liberal arts
    1983 February - Support for projects to improve mathematics education for minority students
    1981 June - To plan and/or launch programs to improve teaching and learning of mathematics re minorities
  - Yale University, 1974-1985 (Box 6, Folder 273)
    1985 June - To support research and writing for a study of the rise of the American research university from 1940 to the present
    1985 January - (820-0741A) Partial support of a research program on economic and quantitative aspects of charitable giving
    1984 September - Support for urban secondary school improvement demonstration projects in New Haven and Los Angeles
    1984 July - Support for southern Africa studies program
    1984 May - (820-0741) Partial support of a research program on the economic and quantitative aspects of charitable giving
    1983 June - Support of recruitment of minorities and financial assistance for students at School of Drama
    1984 March - Support for a Faculty Seminar on Arms Control and International Security
    1982 June - Support for a project to illustrate the quantitative dimensions of America's nonprofit sector to be conducted by the Program on Nonprofit Organizations
    1980 August - Support for Southern Africa studies program, Supplement No. 1
    1980 April - Support of 15 one-year fellowships for working journalists in the Yale Law School Master of Studies in Law Program
    1979 June - Support of a project to improve university teaching and research in the politics of education
    1979 May - Support for an international workshop on the prospects of China's trade and development
    1979 May - Support of five one-year fellowships for working journalists in the Master of Studies in law program
    1978 November - Study of social science as an aid to social problem-solving
    1978 August - Audio-visual treatment of the life and work of Frederick Law Olmsted
    1978 July - Support of five one-year fellowships for working journalists in the Master of Studies in law program
    1977 December - Partial support for research and analysis of America's nonprofit sector
    1977 October - Brandeis University: Dean's discretionary fund for public policy program development. All others: Support of curriculum development and related public policy training activities
    1977 July - Research and training in reproductive science and contraceptive development - Research in contraception and postdoctoral training
    1975 July - Partial support of William Brainard's and F. Trenery Dolbear's research on relative price inflation and indexation
    1974 July - Partial support of planning activities for an experimental undergraduate summer term
    1974 August - Research on problems common to advanced industrial societies - Study of national interests, regional interdependence and integration in Western Europe
    1974 January - General support of the University's Economic Growth Center
    1976 July - To improve and stabilize the financial position of the Yale Repertory Theatre/School of Drama
    1976 September - Support of five one-year fellowships for working journalists in the Master of Studies in Law (MSL) program
    1977 February - Support of five one-year fellowships for working journalists in the Master of Studies in Law program
    1977 May - Support for southern Africa studies program
  - University of Yaounde, 1981 September (Box 6, Folder 274)
    Support for a study of basic health care delivery modes in Cameroon
  - Yarmouk University, Jordan, 1985 March (Box 7, Folder 275)
    Support for strengthening the Institute of Archaeology and Anthropology
  - Yayasan Kusuma Buana (YKB), 1981-1983 (Box 7, Folder 276)
    1983 September - Core support for YKB's experiments in the delivery of family planning and related mother and child health services in Indonesia
    1983 June - Support for the pioneering of a popular approach to breastfeeding and child survival education in Indonesia and the Philippines
    1982 September - Support for contraceptive safety studies
    1981 August - Core support for YKB's experiments in the delivery of family planning and related mother and child health services
  - Yayasan Tengko Situru (Indonesia), 1984 June (Box 7, Folder 277)
    Support for a program to organize poor upland farming communities to intensify farm production and stabilize forest use patterns
  - Yeshiva University, 1974 May (Box 7, Folder 278)
    Support of research on the use of languages of wider communication
  - The Young Filmmakers Foundation, Inc., 1974 October (Box 7, Folder 279)
    Study of the developmental psychology of film composition
  - Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA), 1984 August (Box 7, Folder 280)
    Support for rural leadership skills training and feasibility study of agro-based industry for women
  - Young Women's Christian Association of Jersey City, 1981 June (Box 7, Folder 281)
    Loan to secure financing for the renovation of program space of the YWCA
  - Youth Project, 1978-1985 (Box 7, Folder 282)
    1985 July - Support for a program to provide seed grants and technical assistance to emerging rural organizations
    1983 September - Support for the First Nations Financial Project
    1982 August - Support for the Native American Financial Self-Sufficiency Project
    1981 October - Support for development of a refugee resource and policy center
    1979 November - Support for the Indochinese Refugee Action Center
    1978 February - Financial and technical assistance to local organizations working for tax and school finance reform
  - Youthwork, Inc., 1982 November (Box 7, Folder 283)
    Support for six projects to improve teaching and learning in urban public schools in selected cities and states across the country
  - Government of Zimbabwe (Ministry of Justice and Constitutional Affairs), 1980-1983 (Box 7, Folder 284)
    1983 February - Training of primary court officials
    1980 November - Codification and modernization of customary laws and the training of primary court officials
  - Government of Zimbabwe (Ministry of Public Service), 1980 November (Box 7, Folder 285)
    Repatriation of Zimbabweans selected for senior public service positions
  - Zimbabwe Foundation for Education with Production, 1985 March (Box 7, Folder 286)
    Support for a community theatre project
  - Zimbabwe National Family Planning Council, 1985 May (Box 7, Folder 287)
    Support for the income generation and skills training components of an integrated child spacing program
  - Zimbabwe Project Trust, 1984 June (Box 7, Folder 288)
    Support for the establishment and start-up phase of an employment creation division
  - Zimbabwe Publishing House, 1982 April (Box 7, Folder 289)
    Training of black editors and book production personnel for Zimbabwe and Namibia
  - University of Zimbabwe, 1981-1985 (Box 7, Folder 290)
    1985 January - Social science research unit for communal area management program
    1984 February - Socio-legal research to promote legal reform to enhance the status of women and children
    1983 August - Establishment of a seminar series and a degree-granting program in international studies
    1983 July - Support for a field research and training project in the Department of Land Management
    1983 May - Support for staff and library development at the University of Zimbabwe
    1983 March - Support of curriculum development and policy-related activities in the Department of Law
    1982 November - Socio-legal research to promote legal reform to enhance the status of women and children
    1981 September - Socio-legal research to promote legal reform to enhance the status of women and children
  - Zion Non-Profit Charitable Trust, 1974-1979 (Box 7, Folder 291)
    1979 October - Partial support of a four-year development
    1977 November - Continued support of the Zion Non-Profit Charitable Trust's community development activities
    1974 June - Continued support of the Zion Non-Profit Charitable Trust's community development activities
    1975 November - Continued support of the Zion Non-Profit Charitable Trust's community development activities
  - Zoological Society of London, 1982 February (Box 7, Folder 292)
    Research on post-testicular sperm function and maturation